PATRICK GINLEY JR

13608 KATHLEEN DR. BROOK PARK, OH 44142 PHONE 216-970-1542 · PATGINLEYJR@GMAIL.COM LINKEDIN: /patrick-ginley | GITHUB: github.com/GinleyP87 PORTFOLIO: https://fierce-waters-57309.herokuapp.com/

OBJECTIVE

I possess a diverse background with over 8 years of hands-on working experience within a variety of roles, which I have met or exceeded the needs of various institutions. My dedication, accuracy, and keen eye for detail are just a few descriptors of my work ethic. My strong written and verbal communication skills facilitate a mutual understanding of concepts to personnel on various organizational levels. Lastly, I'm an aspiring full-stack web developer with a deep desire to learn and was recently certified in full-stack development through Case Western Reserve and Trilogy Education Services.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Certification in Bootcamp
- Certification in Brazing, Rigging, and OSHA 30
- HTML 5
- Javascript ES6
- SQL/NoSQL
- MongoDB
- Express
- React
- JQuery
- Node

- Handlebars
- Bootstrap
- GitHub
- Training
- Quality Assurance
- Operational Improvements
- Product Management
- Microsoft Office Products
- Business Development

PROJECTS

Stock-Watch | https://github.com/awolrob/stock-watch | www.stockwatch.life

- Stock watching app that allows creation of an account, sign in, search for stocks, save them to a dashboard, and track their trends.
- Responsibilities included some Javascript functions, Graph QL, and authentication.
- HTML, CSS, Javascript, Mongoose, Express, Graph QL, Node.js,

Can-I-Camp | https://github.io/awolrob/Project1 | https://github.com/awolrob/Project1www.stockwatch.life

- Website that searches for National Parks by state. When selecting a state, a map pops up of all the Nation Parks. Click on one, and it adds the parks to a list on the side.
- Responsibilities included styling the page with CSS and some javascript work.
- HTML, CSS, Javascript, Google Maps API

Work Day Scheduler | https://github.com/GinleyP87/work-day-scheduler | https://ginleyp87.github.io/work-day-scheduler/

- Application that allows tracking of your work day. Create and save notes or benchmarks for each hour. Hours are kept track of by color, updated by moment.js.
- Responsibilities include all Javascript functionality.
- HTML, CSS, Javascript, moment is

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Pipefitters Local Union 120, Cleveland, OH 2019- Present: Journeyman

Accomplishments:

- Help implement new hire training processes and train apprentices who were new to the union.
- I was the acting liaison between the General Contract/Foreman and communicated the daily goals and varies needs to co-workers.
- Help reduce costs on various projects by helping implement new processes and gained insight on the purchase of materials.

Responsibilities:

- Fabricate, assemble, configure, and maintain heating/cooling/sprinkler systems for new and pre-existing domestic, commercial, and industrial venues.
- Train new hires on basic job functions and safety protocols.
- Attend meetings to discuss any business development and alterations to the job site or blueprints.
- Attend varies meetings to ensure safety protocols and review OSHA regulations.
- Work closely in a team environment to handle daily tasks and obstacles that relate to the design of a system or its functionality.
- Responsible for rigging solutions for sprinkler pipe and sprinkler heads while pipes are being lifted by machinery to ensure the pipes are attached safely.

Pipefitters Local Union 120, Cleveland, OH 2014-2019: Apprentice

Accomplishments:

- Review and recommend new processes during my new hire training.
- Absorbed hands on skills and good practices
- Attained various certifications to widen skill set

Responsibilities:

- Attended bi-weekly classes to learn various skills and gain knowledge of the pipefitter trade for Local Union 120.
- Completed all OSHA training and certifications to ensure the safety of myself and coworkers.
- Reviewed job sites to confirm that quality assurance standards were being met sufficiently.
- Followed any instructions provided from the journeyman pipefitters in the field.

The Exchange, Parma, OH

2013-2014: Customer Sales Representative

Responsibilities:

- Utilized critical thinking and service skills to surmise a customer's wants and needs
- Tailor specific choices and recommendations for patrons in a retail sales environment while maintaining an engaging and comfortable customer experience to build long-term relationships.
- Organize and take stock regularly
- Communicate with other branches to locate and secure a product not in stock on location

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: Case Western Reserve University, 10900 Euclid Ave, Cleveland OH, 44106, The Laura and Alvin Siegal Lifelong Learning Program

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.